# MEHDI MAROUANI

Senior software engineer

Phone: (+216) 99 334 081

Email: mehdi.marouani.developer@gmail.com

Location: Bizerte, Tunisia, 7000

Website: mehdi-marouani.netlify.app
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/mehdi-marouani

GitHub: github.com/mehdi049

Upwork: upwork.com/mehdi-marouani

I am a passionate web developer with +9 years of experience creating web applications that range from simple to complex, and I am fully committed to every project. Happy to work alone or within a team as I am self-organized, fast learner, motivated, and like to do things the right way.

Feel free to check out my Upwork profile and find out what my clients are saying about my work.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

 NextJS / ReactJS
 Redux / useContext
 FIGMA to web page
 Tailwind / Material-UI / Bootstrap

 Typescript
 Cypress
 API integration
 Strapi
 GIT
 Agile practices
 Storybook

 SQL
 .Net core
 Entity framework / Dapper
 Microservice architecture

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Vistaprint, <a href="https://www.vistaprint.com">https://www.vistaprint.com</a>
Senior Software Engineer – Tunis, Tunisia – (full remote)

February 2019-Present

- Assisted junior developers and implemented multiple feature-rich releases for our supply chain online business.
- Successfully led the migration of our web application from .Net framework to .Net core / ReactJS, resulting in increased performance by over 100%.
- Assisted in designing and extending our micro-service architecture resulting in fewer dependencies and 50% fast deployment.
- Collaborated with the team and the product owner to create and assign tickets for each sprint.
- Successfully reduced manual tasks for suppliers and plant users, saving the company +5k monthly.
- Assessed interviewing candidates (technical and behaviour interviews).

#### Junior Software Engineer – (On site)

February 2018-February 2019

- Completed assigned tasks within deadlines and demonstrated willingness to learn new technologies.
- Enhanced the UI layout and made the web portal fully responsive, increasing client usage by 150%.
- Actively participated in Agile sprint planning, stand-ups, and retrospectives.

# AllAboutOnline Web developer - Gloucester, United Kingdom - (On site)

Mars 2015-February 2017

- Converted Photoshop wireframes into a fully functional web applications.
- Met with potential clients and suggested solutions for their businesses.

#### FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

#### **Flitter**, <a href="https://www.flitter.fr">https://www.flitter.fr</a>

Lead front-end developer - Paris, France - (full remote)

January 2022-January 2024

- Translated Figma design wireframes into responsive interactive web pages.
- Optimized front-end code for improved performance and scalability.
- Integrated RESTful API to display dynamic content on the web application.
- Worked closely with back-end developers to implement front-end components with server-side logic.

### Upwork, <a href="https://upwork.com">https://upwork.com</a> Senior web developer

January 2021 – January 2022

Top-Rated-Plus freelancer (top 3%) with +20 projects completed successfully and 100% job success rate. link to my profile.

- Worked with different clients and several project that range from a simple contact form to more complex web applications.
- Developed a set of skills that enabled me to meet tight deadlines and handle multiple projects.

#### **EDUCATION**

Private School of Engineering and Technology – ESPRIT / Tunis, Tunisia

2012-2015

IT Engineering degree

ISET Rades / Tunis, Tunisia IT Bachelor degree

2009-2012

## LANGUAGES

**English** – Fluent – B2

French - Fluent

Arabic - Native